Records of the Tucson Meet Yourself Festival, 1974-1996
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Records of the Tucson Meet Yourself Festival, 1974-1996
SWF 012
Southwest Foklore Center
Correspondence, financial records, publicity, photographs, slides, audio tape reels and tape reel transcripts documenting the Tucson Meet Yourself festival from 1974 to 1996.
32 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://www.library.arizona.edu/speccoll
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on the collection
Biographical Note
>Tucson Meet Yourself was an annual folklife festival. It was conceived by James S. and Loma Griffith and Mary Sowls, a member of the Cultural Exchange Council, which was then part of Una Noche Plateada. The first festival was held in October, 1974. From the beginning the Cultural Exchange Council (C.E.C.) of Tucson was the major sponsor, although the festival was actually administered by a group separate from the C.E.C. James S. Griffith served as coordinator until the festival ended in October, 1994. In 1994 the Griffiths retired from the festival. At that time, the name was changed to the Tucson Heritage Experience (T.H.E.) festival. (This description taken from comments provided by James S. Griffith.)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series
Series I: General Files, 1974-1994
Series II:Photographs and Slides, 1975-1994
Series III:Sound Tape Reels and CDs, 1975-1996
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, financial records, publicity, photographs, slides, sound reel tapes and transcripts documenting the activities of the Tucson Meet Yourself festival from its inception in 1974 up to the final festival sponsored and organized by the Southwest Folklore Center in 1994, with audio materials for 1996. General files include correspondence, volunteer files, financial records, and publicity relating to food and craftbooths, folk artists, musicians, and dancers, workshops and contests. An estimated 400 to 500 photographs and slides exist for each year which cover every aspect of the festival including booths, artists, musicians, dancers, performances, and volunteer workers. 324 reel-to-reel tape recordings cover the main stage performances, interviews and workshops. Performances consist primarily of all kinds of ethnic music, but also include the annual corridos competition, fiddle contests, cowboy poetry and storytelling workshops, railroad oral history interviews, personal interviews and workshops. Transcripts are available for many of the reels. Some Reels have been migrated to CDs available for public use.
Folk festivals -- Arizona -- Tucson.; Folk music -- Arizona -- Tucson.; Corridos.; Folk songs, English.; Folk songs, Spanish -- Arizona.; Mexican Americans -- Arizona -- Music.; Indians of North America -- Arizona -- Music.
Container List
- General Files, 1974-1996
  Series I: This series is arranged chronological. It includes the Tape Transcripts, 1974-1994, for the audio materials in Series III Sound Tape Reels and CDs, the General Administrative records, arranged chronologically, for each year of the festival, and a small collection of files concerning the annual corrido contest. The bulk of the material, the General Administrative records, includes, but is not limited to: newspaper clippings, correspondence, press releases, programs, funding and grant paperwork, and photographs. Some oversize publicity materials are stored in Box 28 of collection SWF 013. Note: These contents are unprocessed; the following only represents an inventory of the materials.
  - Tape Transcripts, 1974-1994. (Box 1)
  - General Files, 1974-1981. (Box 2)
  - General Files, 1974-1981. (Box 3)
  - General Files, 1984-1986. (Box 4)
  - General Files, 1987-1989. (Box 5)
  - General Files, 1987-1989. (Box 6)
  - General Files, 1992-1994. (Box 7)
  - General Files, 1974-1996. (Box 8)
  - General Files, 1974-1996 continued and TMY corrido contest files, 1984-1995. (Box 9)
- Sereis II: Photographs and Slides, 1974-1996
  This series is arranged Chronological. Ca. 400 to 500 photographs, slides and negatives for each year of the festival. Most taken by James S. Griffith, Coordinator of the Southwest Folklore Center and principal organizer of the Festival from 1975-1994. The bulk of the material in this series is housed in binders for each year.
  Slides and Photographs
  - 1974-1975, 1977-1978 (Binder 1)
  - 1979-1981 (Binder 2)
  - 1982 (Binder 3)
  - 1983 (Binder 4)
  - 1984 (Binder 5)
  - 1985 (Binder 6)
  - 1985 (Binder 7)
  - 1986 (Binder 8)
  - 1987 (Binder 9)
  - 1988 (Binder 10)
  - 1989-1990 (Binder 11)
  - 1991 (Binder 12)
  - 1992 (Binder 13)
  - 1993 (Binder 14)
  - 1994 (Binder 15)
  - Duplicate Slides (Binder 16)
  - Miscellaneuous Slides, TMY Press Photographs; Sonoran Experience Sunny Side HS Slides,; Negatives for TMY Food Booths,; TMY Photographs,; 35 mm Film,; 1988; 1978; 1993; 1987-1994 (Box 10)
  - Binder 1, Binder 2; Binder 3; Binder 4; Binder 5; Binder 6; Binder 7; Binder 8; 1987; 1988; 1989; 1990; 1991; 1992; 1993; 1994 (Box 11)
- Sereis III: Sound Tape Reels and CDs, 1975-1994
  - Untitled (Box 12)